Biological AI or synthetic AI or maybe
you just want to call it intelligence is
progressing rapidly. This is where we
take biological components and combine
them with artificial intelligence and
one independent researcher did publish
that they had combined brain organoids
with the tiny human brains that you can
grow in a literal jar if you want to
with a language model and that is pretty
neat and we'll talk about it. This
research group made a three-dimensional
harness that can be combined with brain
organoids and it can have continuous
communication back and forth and it can
coat the entire organoid. This chip can
be used in real time to train AI. Yes,
AI can be trained on the spiking
patterns of our own brains with the tiny
brains that we grow.
But why? Why would somebody want to do
this? Well, there are a few reasons. The
one of course is to create artificial
intelligence. The spiking patterns in
our own brains create logic and that
logic can be integrated into an AI.
There are more kinds of AIs than LLMs.
Although those can also be combined with
LLMs. The other reason is that it
creates integration for medical devices.
We are rapidly approaching the point
where strokes can be treated with brain
organoids or even modifications of
existing brains and they're going to
need an interface. That interface could
work either with the brain organoid or
it could work with our own brain. So
yes, figuring out how to communicate
with brain blobs is really useful.
I know the title of this paper is saying
human level models but it doesn't
necessarily mean human level
intelligence although that certainly is
the goal for some. We are looking at
creating logic for artificial
intelligence that's based off of the way
that we think or our brains themselves
at the physical level. If you want a
wild ride of a paper, look at this one.
They want to create bio quantum hybrid
computers. Yes, they want to combine
brain organoids with quantum computers
and honestly, I'm here for it. Let's see
if it'll work.
Now, this was published pretty quietly.
You can search that title up there on
GitHub CL1 LLM encoder.
This is an independent researcher who
rented CL1. So that is the brain
organoid computer that Cortical Labs
created. You can purchase it for about
30k. It is a lot. Either way, they used
it to integrate it into a language
model. This entire workflow could be
used for physical reservoirs, or brains
are technically physical reservoirs.
That is where the physics of the system
itself creates logic.
This has not been peer-reviewed, but I
do kind of want to give this all a try.
I'm interested to see what happens. Now,
I do want to tell you that you don't
need human brain to be a computer. You
can have bacteria be a computer. You can
even create bacterial cells for exactly
the kind of computation you want. And
since logic can arise from their
behaviors, that too can be used as a
computer. So, we don't really need human
brain tissue to be our computers. We can
utilize other forms of life, and there
are benefits to this. We haven't been
able to make true agency, not in
silicone, but life encodes randomness.
Life has desire. So, let's use that. And
I know it does seem like cheating a
little bit if we're borrowing brain
tissue so that it can be artificial
intelligence, or borrowing bacteria,
which arguably have real intelligence.
Yeah. It's more of a cyborg, isn't it?
Large language models are not enough.
They were never enough. We are going to
have to embody our artificial
intelligence, and then they are going to
have to make decisions based on the
environment that they're in. They're
going to have to learn, and if they
learn, they're going to have to
understand the why.
An AI needs to understand if it trips
over a person, that's different than
tripping some laundry. It needs to have
morality. It needs to engage with the
world and sense it, and it needs to have
some skin in the game. Meaning we're
going to have to develop an artificial
intelligence system that cares, and us
humans do not really know how to do
that. And unfortunately, we are making
robots before we figure out how to do
that. So, things will go wrong, and they
are beginning to go wrong.
One of the big ideas is that we have to
have modular systems. So, it has to have
multiple layers of cognition in order to
become truly intelligent. So, it needs
to sense the world. It needs to have
meta-cognition. It needs to dream in
some circumstances.
Yeah, Anthropic did make a press release
that they are now having Claude dream,
which is actually a great idea and I've
seen that integrated into neuromorphic
AI. So, once it finishes for the day,
it's going to process all the
information that it learned and just
pick out what is important and integrate
that.
This is thought to be one of the reasons
that humans dream. I mean, we may sleep
so that we can clear out metabolites
from our brains, just junk that built up
in our cells, but we may also use it in
order to process the information that
we've taken in that we haven't figured
out what to do with because we've had so
much other stuff to pay attention to.
So, yes, a truly intelligent AI will
probably need to have lobes not
dissimilar to our brains and different
processes. I mean, different parts of
our own brains take on different tasks.
You have your brain stem which is taking
on autonomic behaviors. You have to beat
your heart and you have to breathe, but
you have other parts of your brain that
are responsible for cognition.
So, when it comes to LLMs, just give
them a break. They may not have
sensation yet, but we could give them
that. They don't have meta-cognition,
but we could give them that. And
eventually, I think us humans will make
them so similar to ourselves that we
really will have to have the
conversation about whether or not an
artificial intelligence might have
rights.
We are not there yet. And I realize
there's a whole lot of nuance in these
conversations because, you know, AI
tends to promote delusions. So, we have
to be careful about how we speak about
these things, but I do believe we have a
future where something wacky could
happen. I hope you've enjoyed this. If
the robots ever rebel, I will probably
be the first person to tell you about
them and I'm on their side. I love you,
Remer.